[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[thud]
[sizzling]
Hello?
[man laughing]
[sizzling continues]
'What the hell?'
[intense music]
[male #1]
'I appreciate your people coming
in on this, Agent Lisbon.'
'Haven't handled many
homicides. None, in fact.'
Frankly, I'm looking
to learn from you.
Not a problem, Deputy Fisher.
Small town.
We don't get much trouble.
- Well, that's a shame.
- It is?
Trouble's your business.
You could say.
'Victim's Alan Foster,
43 years old'
married, no children. Architect.
He bought the house
a few months back
said he was gonna rehab it.
Was the wife
with him last night?
Uh, no, she was in the city.
They have a house
in San Francisco.
I sent a man
to break the news.
Was anybody else
in the house with him?
'Nobody as far as we can tell.
I don't know what to say.'
'The house was locked up tighter
than a drum when I got here.'
Took me half an hour
just to shut off the alarm.
Cho, check
the alarm system.
Either the victim
let somebody in
or they broke
in someplace.
It's a shame.
Foster seemed like a nice guy.
Whoa, that's a lie.
You didn't like him one bit.
- I-I didn't say that.
- Yes, you did.
You thought he was rich,
arrogant, pretentious
an interloper. He wore those
trendy architect's glasses.
[chuckles]
Did you kill him?
- Did I..
- 'Hmm?'
- Hmm?
- 'No.'
No.
[instrumental music]
What kind of question is that?
[sighs]
He's got something in his hand.
- Jane, gloves.
- Right.
[Lisbon]
'A brass button
with the letter B?'
That mean something
to you, deputy?
No.
What's this guy's problem?
That would take way
too long to answer.
Let's take a look inside.
Okay. It's this way.
[music continues]
Clear signs of struggle
rules out suicide.
That, and suicides usually open
the window before they jump.
What's troubling you, Fisher?
What? Nothing.
What are you talking about?
That button made
your pupils dilate.
Now you've gone pale.
What's up, Fisher?
What's troubling you?
Well, it occurred
to me that the button
could stand for Beckworth
'and I got a little
chill, that's all.'
- Who's Beckworth?
- Walter Beckworth.
He was the original owner
of this house, built it.
Died 80 something years ago.
People say he...
haunts the place.
I've heard the stories
since I was a kid
but nobody believes them.
Right.
Guy from the security
company ran the alarm history.
It's been armed
from six last night
until the deputies
turned it off this morning.
No alarms
or interruptions of service.
As far as I can tell
no one's entered
or left this building
except the victim.
But that's impossible.
Isn't it?
Spooky.
[theme music]
I'm not saying volunteering
is better work than this
but it makes me feel better
at the end of the day.
I see people smiling
because of what I've done.
There's something,
I don't know, joyous in it.
How often do we see
people smile in this job?
Leaving out crazy? Never.
The coroner took Foster's body.
I'm gonna get his wife
and bring her to the office.
Lisbon and Jane
are up on the porch.
Okay, thanks.
She's volunteering
at a homeless kitchen.
- That's cool.
- There's a man there.
I think she's, uh, you know.
Banging a homeless guy?
No! A volunteer.
A chef. And she's not..
I don't know.
Not yet...maybe. I think..
I don't know...no.
Dude, you need counseling.
[instrumental music]
[Lisbon]
'Somehow the killer
got into the house'
without tripping the alarm
or turning it off.
So the killer didn't come
through the front door.
[Lisbon]
'Probably found some kind
of hole in the system.'
Check the grounds
and inside the house.
- Find out how they got in.
- On it.
Grace, you're
the spiritual sort.
Do you believe in ghosts?
I believe the spirit
survives death
and a troubled spirit
can make itself known.
Oh, come on. You don't seriously
think there's a ghost here.
Meh. I don't know.
If you see one, let me know.
[instrumental music]
How long had your husband been
staying at Beckworth Mansion
Mrs. Foster?
Off and on for about three weeks
since we closed on it.
Why? It's pretty run-down.
To get a feel for the house
before he worked on it.
He said you should
spend a month in a house
before you thought
about changing it.
He's conscientious that way.
Or was conscientious that way.
We can take a break
if you'd like.
No, no, no. Let's,
let's just get through it.
So you were at home the night
of your husband's murder?
Yes.
We have to ask
is there anyone
who can verify that?
Um, no, I was alone.
Alan had been at
the mansion all week.
Was it common for you and your
husband to be apart that long?
It was not uncommon
when he started a project.
He...got immersed.
Who might have wanted
to hurt your husband?
Oh, I can tell you
who was angry with him.
- Victoria Abner.
- Who's she?
She's this hippie-dippie
woman who lives in town
and she weaves linens and rugs.
She used to own Beckworth.
She's a descendant
of the man who built it.
And she resented your
husband for buying the place?
But not at first.
There were tax issues
that came with the property
so we thought she'd
be glad to be rid of it.
But...about a week
after we closed
she just blew up, claimed
that Alan stole the house.
It was vicious.
Did she ever
threaten your husband?
[Mrs. Foster]
'She sent some
pretty scary e-mails.'
[knocking on glass]
Excuse me.
What?
Walter Beckworth
was killed
in 1928.
Fight over a woman.
You know how?
No, and I don't care.
He was thrown out of
the exact same window
that Alan Foster was
thrown out of. Coincidence?
- Yes.
- Yeah. Well, it's all here.
- Is that, uh, Foster's widow?
- Mm-hmm.
I need to talk to her.
Mrs. Foster, Patrick Jane.
Did your husband see or hear
anything odd at the mansion
strange sightings,
unusual noises, apparitions?
As a matter of fact, Alan did
mention some strange things.
What kind of things?
Um, in the last week or so
he heard some noises
at night, like groans.
He said sometimes it looked
like things were being moved.
I know it's a little creepy,
but Alan wasn't too bothered.
'He was used to old houses.'
What does this have
to do with how he died?
Victoria Abner
has no arrests
but three years ago
a neighbor took out
a restraining order
against her.
Some argument about
the neighbor's dog.
Victoria got a little
in-your-face about it.
Uh, go and see how
mad she really was
about Foster
buying the mansion.
Okay.
And be sure to ask
about the ghost too.
Do notask about ghosts.
Don't you think I know what
you're doing? No ghosts.
The ghost has something
to do with Foster's death.
No, it doesn't,
because ghosts don't exist.
They don't exist in yourmind,
but if you believe they exist
then...they exist.
[Rigsby]
'Anything?'
No pry marks on any
of the frames so far
no footprints
under the windows.
I don't see any
sign of forced entry.
Maybe itwasa ghost.
Ghosts don't throw
200-pound men out windows.
What do ghosts do?
I have no idea.
Let's just check
the other side.
So you gonna keep volunteering
at the, uh, kitchen?
Oh, yeah.
Making a lot of, uh,
new friends, I expect.
I am, yeah, that's
the great thing
about doing volunteer work.
You meet so many new people
that have the same kind
of values
and interests as you.
Right.
- Hey, look at that.
- What?
The lock on the door, looks new.
Someone cut it open.
[door creaking]
[intense music]
Well, if they haven't started
work on the house yet..
All the power tools are missing.
What's there?
You think ghosts smoke filtered?
Boss, someone broke
into a storage area
'stole a whole bunch
of equipment and supplies.'
'Maybe they broke
into the house too.'
[instrumental music]
Can I help you?
I see you specialize
in local history, Mr..
Raimey. Philip Raimey.
Yes, and you are?
Looking for information
on Walter Beckworth.
Are you with the police?
Here about the Foster incident?
Yes.
But don't tell anyone.
Patrick Jane.
Well, Mr. Jane
if it's Beckworth
you're interested in
you've come to
the right place.
[music continues]
Thank you.
Agent Cho, of course
I was angry with Foster.
If someone stole your home,
wouldn't you be angry as well?
- He bought the house, Mrs.--
- You don't understand.
A house you haven't lived
in since you were a child.
That's not the point.
Sorry. I didn't know
you were with somebody.
Oh, this is my nephew, Drew.
Agent Cho is asking
questions about Alan Foster.
He wants to know
why I was so upset
with the man who
stole Beckworth.
- It is a complicated issue.
- No, it's not that complicated.
There are many factors
to be considered
economic and emotional.
My nephew is a lawyer.
He's very sensible.
That's good,
because I'm not.
There are no
factors to consider.
Foster was a thief and a liar.
You couldn't afford
the taxes on the house.
You were grateful when
he first purchased it.
What changed your mind?
You have a very good aura.
Thank you.
Excellent color, deep red..
...grounded, realistic.
And Foster's aura...was pink.
Dirty pink.
That's dishonesty,
fecklessness.
When he came to me, he said
he wanted to preserve Beckworth.
He lied to me.
He wanted to gut it,
my childhood home.
'I couldn't let him do that.'
Look, agent,
the Beckworth mansion
is understandably a very
emotional subject for my family
but whatever she
may have felt or said
my aunt is incapable
of hurting anybody.
Where were you last night?
In my home.
In my bed.
Not killing Alan Foster.
- What about you?
- I was here.
I've been staying
with my aunt on and off
ever since she was
forced to sell the place.
He's been helping me out
with my legal things.
I'd be lost without him.
Tax liens and escrow,
nothing too complicated.
[cell phone rings]
Excuse me.
Cho.
Cho, did you ask
about the ghost?
No, you heard Lisbon.
Uh-h-h.
I am talking
to the local historian.
Apparently, Beckworth was
deeply involved in spiritualism.
Liked to explore
the world beyond
held seancesand all
that kind of malarkey.
So ghosts are relevant, my
friend. This is very important.
Cho, don't leave me hanging.
Ma'am, do you know anything
about a ghost at the mansion?
Of course.
That's the spirit
of my grandfather
Walter Beckworth.
He used to visit me
when I was a child.
- She says there's a ghost.
- Thank you.
No surprise there.
[sniffs]
Mmm. Clover honey?
Yes, as a matter of fact it is.
[Jane]
'Mmm.'
- Jane?
- Mm. Sorry.
Uh, Mr. Raimey says there's
also a hidden treasure there.
Uh, rumored treasure,
purely rumored.
Rumored treasure, some fortune
Beckworth hid in the house.
[Jane on phone]
'Does Abner know
anything about that?'
- Beckworth's treasure?
- Oh, yes.
Everybody in the family
knew that there was a great
mythic treasure. We gave up
looking for it years ago.
It was a fraud. If it wasn't,
do you think I'd be living here?
She says no treasure.
Hmm. Got it. Thank you.
Okay.
No treasure.
'Clover honey.'
Ah.
Well...ahem...thank you.
[instrumental music]
If there is anything
else I can do..
Well, there is one more thing.
H-how did Beckworth
make his money?
Oh, he was a bootlegger,
very successful one.
It's in, uh, that one,
the second from the bottom.
Okay. Thank you.
Uh, d-did you ever
cross paths with Foster?
Once or twice.
He seemed pleasant enough.
Never paid very much attention.
You deceitful
old bag of bones.
- Excuse me?
- You heard me.
[Rigsby]
'Nothing on
the exterior of the house.'
Let's check inside.
- That's weird.
- What?
Thought this was shut.
[creaking]
[rattling]
- Did you hear that?
- Yeah. Someone's upstairs.
I thought everybody left.
[instrumental music]
Hello?
[thud]
It came from in there.
[sizzling]
Old wiring, I guess.
[man laughing]
What was that?
CBI. Come out.
[door creaks]
[door bangs shut]
Police, whoever you are,
come out of the room
'with your hands
above your head.'
[male #2]
'Grace. Over here.'
[instrumental music]
Boo!
Jane?
[door bangs shut]
- Where'd he go?
- How'd he do that?
It's easy. I'll show you.
'Ah, you see?'
It's all switches.
[sizzling]
There's a system
of pipes that carry
sound throughout the house.
[laughing]
- Hello?
- Yeah. It's all fake.
Because, my credulous Van Pelt,
spirits are smoke and mirrors
and that's all that they are.
And the ghost?
How did you do that?
Ah, the piece de resistance.
If you could stand in
the corner, my friend Rigsby
and, Grace, if you could take
your place out by the doors.
Pepper's ghost.
It's an old conjurer's trick,
a simple optical illusion.
All you need is a sheet of glass
that slides out of the wall..
It's a reflection?
And lighting.
[sizzling]
[chuckles]
[chuckling continues]
And off.
And Beckworth had all this built
just so he could hold seances?
So he could amaze
and terrify his guests
with his mastery of the occult,
and it's been used recently.
Someone has
cleaned the dust off.
So somebody was
trying to scare Foster.
- Mm-hmm.
- Why?
And how did they
get in the house?
The alarm would have
been on the whole time.
Come with me.
Beckworth was a bootlegger
during prohibition
which meant he had
to smuggle liquor
into the house
and hide it someplace
the authorities
couldn't find it.
This house is riddled
with secret passages.
Including ones
that lead outside?
[creaking]
Voila.
Head down. Take a look.
I'll check the outside walls.
No doubt one of us will
find the secret passage.
- After you.
- Oh, thank you.
[indistinct singing]
[bell ringing]
- Jeb Haas?
- Who wants to know?
- Agent Lisbon, CBI.
- Pretty little thing like you?
I have some questions for you
regarding Alan Foster's murder.
I got nothing to tell you.
Looks like there were some
construction supplies stolen
around the time of the murder.
Deputy Fisher says
you're the local thief
most likely to steal
that kind of stuff.
Fisher sent you?
That son of a bitch.
I don't know what
he told you but, uh..
...I don't know anything
about a break-in or any murder.
Then you won't mind coming
down to the station with me.
What if I don't want to go?
Sir, this doesn't
have to be difficult.
[intense music]
- You okay?
- Yeah, yeah. You?
Hey, look at that.
Wine cellar.
Wonder if any of
it's still good.
I doubt it.
[rustling]
- What was that?
- Eh, probably rats.
Oh, God, no. I hate rats.
- Oh, it's just a ghost then.
- You don't believe in ghosts.
Yeah, but you do.
Wait upstairs, if you like.
- I'll take this one.
- Oh, thanks. That's okay.
Same night that
Foster was killed
you broke into his pool house
and stole a few thousand dollars
worth of tools and equipment.
We know because we found
some of the stolen equipment
in your vehicle,
and we found this
cigarette butt
in the pool house.
It'll definitely
have your DNA on it.
Everybody knows that
place is all wired up
with some fancy alarm system.
I didn't kill anybody.
I never saw Foster, and I
never went into his house.
- Nice if you could prove that.
- I can't.
But I do have some
particular information
on that evening...
information that you want.
- Okay.
- Uh-uh.
Not until I get
a deal on the theft
and the breaking
and entering charges.
- A good one too.
- You want a deal? Okay.
And just to be clear,
is this a deal for the theft
and B&E alone,
or the tax evasion as well?
What?
According to your IRS records
you haven't filed
a tax return since 2002.
Unless you haven't earned
a dime in income in seven years
you're facing some pretty
serious tax evasion charges.
Do you have any idea how much
prison time that carries?
- Prison time?
- 'Serious time, massive fines.'
I'm gonna let you
think about it.
When I was loading stuff
out of the pool house..
...I saw a car in
the woods, a black BMW.
'There was somebody sitting in'
the driver's seat...
Foster's wife.
Lillian Foster?
I've seen her in town.
She sat there the whole time.
She never even noticed me.
She just stared at the house.
Was she still
there when you left?
Yes.
So you'll do something,
I mean, about the tax thing?
Don't worry.
I was lyin' about that.
- What's wrong with it?
- I don't know.
Maybe the batteries.
Don'thitit.
Fine. You fix it then.
Let's just use mine.
- Ah!
- What? What? What?
Oh, I felt something
crawling up my leg.
- Well, is it still there?
- No.
It was probably just a ghost.
- Grace?
- Yes?
I..
Never mind.
- Maybe we should keep going.
- Yeah.
Grace, I love you.
I've loved you from
the first moment I met you.
Screw the rules.
Screw the CBI. I need you.
I, uh-uh...that's, um..
Unless you stop me,
I'm gonna kiss you now.
[rattling]
Eureka!
Found it!
Good work.
Yeah, we'll meet you
back at the office
after we pick up
Lillian Foster.
We're outside
her house now.
Jane says he found another
entrance to the mansion.
I knew there had
to be another way in.
[Lillian]
'How dare you come here?
My husband just died.'
Is that Victoria Abner
and her nephew?
What are they doing here?
Have you no shame?
Mrs. Foster, if you could
just please calm down.
You know what you are?
You're a vulture.
You're a crazy,
obsessed old vulture!--
That mansion is mine.
It belongs to myfamily.
I will burn it down before
you step foot in that place!
Lady, you need psychiatric help.
- Oh, yeah?
- Hey-hey!
[grunting]
Hey! Break it up!
Get her off of me now!
What the hell is
the matter with you?
You have no class!
You're the one
that came to my house!
[indistinct shouting]
[Victoria]
'Oh, yeah, I'mthe crazy bitch?'
How you feeling,
Mrs. Foster?
Embarrassed.
How'd you get into
the ruckus with Ms. Abner?
She came by to ask if she could
rent the mansion back from me
seeing as how I won't
want to be living there.
Did she say why?
I, uh, didn't wait
to hear the details.
She had been plaguing us
all this time, and now this?
[sighs]
I'm afraid I just...lost it.
There is something else we
wanted to talk to you about.
You weren't in San Francisco
the night of your
husband's murder.
You were at the mansion.
You know about that?
- Why'd you lie to us?
- I was ashamed.
Of what?
Of why I was there
in the first place.
- And why was that?
- She was spying on her husband.
She suspected him
of being unfaithful.
Yes. How did you know that?
Because he's been
unfaithful before?
Yes.
He had an affair
about a year ago.
He was out of town,
I was caught up with my work
and...it happened.
That's very
understanding of you.
Oh, I was furious, believe me.
But we worked on it,
counseling and so forth
and I thought I had moved on.
But I hadn't.
I didn't trust him.
So, when Alan told me he
would be spending this weekend
at the mansion
and wouldn't be coming home..
...I decided I had to go
there to catch him in the act.
But no one showed up.
No.
I felt so awful that I
left without talking to him.
- What time did you leave?
- Around ten.
Is there any way
to prove that?
Um, I bought gas
on the way home.
The credit card company will
have a record of that, right?
Yes, we'll verify that.
I can't help thinking
that if I'd stayed there
if I'd just gone
and talked to Alan
he would still be alive.
Mmm, most likely
you'd both be dead.
With the way that I feel,
I might prefer that.
That feeling will pass.
What do you know about that?
Enough.
- How you doing, Drew?
- Fine.
Thank you. Thanks.
Now your aunt's gonna be
in with us a little longer.
This fight's gonna take
some sorting out, okay?
[sighs]
I tried to stop it
from escalating.
That's why I was there
in the first place
but the hostility just
kind of caught me off guard.
It'll be up to your aunt
whether or not to press charges
but you're a lawyer.
You know the deal.
Well, I'm not
exactly a lawyer.
My aunt likes to exaggerate.
I'm a paralegal.
Cho, uh, I'm sorry.
You got a second?
Sure. We're still gonna
need a statement from you.
Excuse me for a second.
- What's up?
- I told Grace I love her.
Wow. Okay. Well done.
Then what happened?
Oh, nothing,
Jane interrupted
and she hasn't
said a word since.
- So tell her again.
- Right, okay.
Tell her again.
Yeah, alright.
Your aura is
fascinating, Mr. Jane.
So many hues.
Thank you.
The mansion's uninhabitable.
Why would you want it back?
Sentimental reasons.
Mmm, no.
No, that's not right.
You're closed, furtive.
You're hiding something.
There's something in
that house, isn't there?
Something you don't want
anyone else to find..
...evidence of
your guilt, perhaps.
That's absurd.
No, yeah, you're right.
That is absurd.
It's something
else entirely.
Ah...the treasure.
[chuckles]
What treasure?
Walter Beckworth's treasure
he hid in the mansion.
I wanted my house back
because I didn't like
what Foster planned for it.
He was going to destroy it.
[Lisbon]
'Foster had only
been there a few weeks.'
How could you have known what
he was gonna do before he did?
In conversation, he told me.
Ma'am, we find out you're lying,
you become suspect number one.
Alright.
How are you with riddles?
[chuckles]
I found the clue
a few weeks ago
when I bought some
of Beckworth's papers
at an estate sale.
It was in a letter
to one of his cousins
just before his death.
Beckworth boasts that he's
hidden his great treasure
where no one
can find it
and then he
offers this clue
"If fortune is
what you seek sincere
the only place
to look is here."
That's it?
That's the riddle?
- Yes.
- Interesting.
Of course, I told
Mrs. Abner right away
but the house had already
been sold to Foster.
Why didn't you
mention this before?
Well, it-it...
it didn't seem relevant.
It's motive. It's very relevant.
Mr. Raimey and Ms. Abner
had agreed to keep quiet
to avoid having to share the
loot with anyone else, correct?
Yes, but that doesn't mean
either of us killed Foster.
Oh, absolutely right.
Whoever killed
Foster was simply
trying to scare
him from the mansion.
It could have been anyone
that wanted the treasure
even you, Deputy Fisher.
That's right. I killed him.
Did you? You denied it earlier.
Stop doing that.
I need to see this clue.
Where's the letter?
Thank you.
[sniffs]
- What?
- Smells good.
"If fortune is
what you seek sincere
the only place
to look is... hear."
"Hear."
It's spelled H-E-A-R.
Well, I assumed
it was a mistake.
Hmm. There are no mistakes.
Let's go.
[instrumental music]
[door closes]
[indistinct chattering]
[clears throat]
As you know, Walter Beckworth
left a coded message
describing the location
of his treasure.
I brought you all here
to help me find it.
The word "here" is
misspelled in the riddle.
I don't believe
that's a mistake.
I think..
...that the clue itself
lies in that word
hear, H-E-A-R.
What comes to mind
when I say the word hear?
Noise.
- Sounds.
- Ears.
Very good. What else?
Music.
Musical instruments.
Definite possibility.
Cho?
[instrumental music]
Unveil it.
[creaks]
[piano music]
[tapping]
[tapping continues]
Mmm. Aha.
What is it?
Yeah, what is it?
Beckworth's fortune.
[exhales deeply]
[Raimey]
'There's nothing in it.'
[Drew]
'It's empty?'
[Jane]
Wait.
[Victoria]
'What is that?'
It's another riddle.
What does it say?
"To find fortune and riches,
one doesn't need help.
All one must do
is look to oneself."
What does it mean?
I don't know,
but it's spelled correctly.
It means we're
wasting our time.
It doesn't even make any sense.
Let's not rush to judgment.
Beckworth probably put it
there as a practical joke.
Pretty lame joke.
But the fortune
could still be here.
I just need time to find it.
We're not gonna
waste any more time.
I'm shutting this down.
Everybody out.
'Cho, secure the place
and set the alarm.'
'Have Rigsby and Van Pelt
set up on the mansion tonight.'
'We'll take
the shift after them.'
Nobody gets in this place
especially Jane. Understood?
- Got it. Everybody out.
- 'L-Lisbon.'
Lisbon. I, you, I-I,
this, Lisbon, this--
Bite me.
We're done for the night.
"Bite me?"
- It's too much?
- Uh, a smidge.
Worked. It's fine.
Just a little over-the-top.
[crickets chirping]
- So, uh, Grace..
- Yes?
...I was wondering
if we could..
- How do you wanna handle this?
- Handle what?
The stakeout.
Oh. Um, right.
Listen, about
the other thing..
...it's, I, uh..
Maybe it's not
the right time.
Yeah. Yeah.
Um...we could, uh, walk.
Patrol the grounds.
Or maybe one of us
could stay here
while the other one
patrols alternate?
Yep, that's better.
I'll, uh, I'll go first.
Oh, that's okay.
I can do it.
[Rigsby]
I'm easy.
[Grace]
'Well, if you wanna go
first, that's fine also.'
[Rigsby]
No, no. No.
[intense music]
[creaking]
"Look to oneself."
[music continues]
[shattering]
No.
There's nothin' there,
Drew. Never was.
You planted the second clue?
Aha. Yes.
I didn't kill Foster.
Don't be ridiculous.
Of course, you did.
Only the killer knew
how to get in here
viathe secret passageway.
You proved your guilt
just by walking in the room.
[sighs]
Was it all just
for the money?
"Justfor the money?"
I spent years listening
to my family go on
about the Beckworths
and everything that they had.
'I didn't get any of it.'
Not one thing.
And then my aunt told me
about the clue and the treasure
and I thought...I could
get that for myself.
I could have what I've
deserved all my life.
All I had to do was get
Foster out of the house.
So you haunted him.
My cousin told me
about the, uh, equipment
Beckworth had built in.
I just wanted to scare him.
[Drew]
But Foster
wouldn't take a hint.
So I had to do something.
[growly]
You.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, hey, stop!
Hey, stop!
I didn't mean to kill him.
[intense music]
Oh, I didn't know what to do.
And then, uh, I remembered
the stories about Beckworth
how he was killed, how his
ghost still haunts this place.
So I threw him out the window
the same way
Beckworth was killed.
It wasn't Foster's house.
It belonged to myfamily.
Put your hands
behind your back.Now.
When you first opened
the box under the piano
was there anything in it?
Mmm..
...this.
You killed Foster
for an old key.
I wonder what it opens.
- Oh, I know what it opens.
- What?
He's just messing with you.
He's mean like that.
'Come on.'
Mr. Jane.
I was just being briefed
by one of your agents.
Well, I hope they
conducted themselves
in a professional manner.
Thank you...for everything.
Well, my pleasure.
Do you mind a question?
Uh...no.
I asked about you.
What happened to your
family, I'm very sorry.
And I thought...maybe
it means you understand
how it feels
to lose somebody.
Was that your question?
Do you think they
know how we feel?
The dead, I mean..
...how sorry we are..
...how we wish things
could be different?
[crying]
Do you think
they understand?
[instrumental music]
No.
Sorry.
[sniffles]
Case closed pizza?
Case closed pizza.
Rigsby eats all the sausage
again, I'll be pissed.
- Are you okay?
- Right as rain.
Oh, I have the perfect
thing to go with this.
- Wine?
- Yeah.
Just a little
something special.
Excuse me.
I need a glass. Sorry.
Sure.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
I'm gonna leave
in a few minutes.
Wait five,
then meet me at my car.
- Okay.
[music continues]
Just a little.
- Please.
- Thanks.
- Mr. Rigsby.
- Cheers.
Case closed.
[all]
- Mmm. It's nice.
- Glad you like it.
So what was the key to, Jane?
The one you found in the box.
- The key? Beckworth's fortune.
- Give it up.
Well, just because the fortune
wasn't gold or cash
doesn't mean it doesn't exist.
- So what was it?
- Beckworth was a collector.
He collected
hundreds of one thing
some of the finest,
rarest examples in the world
worth tens
of millions of dollars.
- So what was it?
- Mmm.
- 'What?'
- Smells good.
[instrumental music]
Cheers.
[theme music]